

- 7 Years 6 Months
- dksingh413@gmail.com
- . (+91) 8459916846
- https://www.linkedin.com/i n/dharmendra-kumarsingh-480ba2a0/



Key Skills

React.js Node.js

Express

MongoDB

MySQL

AWS

API

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Angular



Personal Information

City New Delhi

Country INDIA



Languages

English, Hindi

Dharmendra Kumar Singh

Full Stack Development



Profile Summary

With nearly 8 years of experience in Full Stack Developer, I have excelled in roles focusing on Web Development, Applications Development, and API development across Edtech, Health, and Ecommerce sectors. Recognized for efficient system design and implementation, I am currently expanding my skills in React, Node, Express, MongoDB, MySQL and AWS. Excellent problem-solving and communication skills and demonstrates a passion for learning and implementing new technologies.



Education

2022, Distance Learning

MCA, Computers

Swami Vivekanand Subharti University

2013, Full Time

BCA, Computers **BRABU, Muzaffarpur**

2010

12th, Bihar



Work Experience

2022 / 2024

Full Stack Developer

HPL Security Pvt. Ltd

Key Result Area

Working as a Full Stack Developer at HPL Security, developing Edtech solutions and Institute Management Solutions. Skilled in application design, web and mobile API development, and continuous learning in AWS, Docker and Next. Js. Recognized for efficient Application design. Proficient in React, Node, Express, MongoDB, MySQL, JavaScript, Git, Jira, Slack and more, with expertise in overall system design and team management. Proficient in designing and implementing scalable solutions, leveraging React and Node to optimize system performance and enhance user experience.

Achieved increase in system efficiency through the successful.

2019 - 2022

Full Stack Developer(DM-IT)

M & J Edtech Pvt. Ltd.

Led the development of a website and Application on GuruQ, GuruQ is the name of the Project, so we provide the dashboard of Tutor Student and Institute for mange our profile like how to take a class and how to provide a class through GuruQ Mobile Application and Web Application. Proficient in React, Node, Express, MongoDB, MySQL, JavaScript, Git, Jira, Slack and more, Student take online and off line class without any third party tools. Spearheaded the development of innovative solutions and automated work procedures, drove efficiency and enhanced product quality.

2018 - 2019

Sr. Software Developer

Primo Group Pvt. Ltd.

Key Result Area

Full Stack Developer to obtain a position with a progressive web development or software development company with a strong focus on creativity and problem solving. To support a network infrastructure based on multiple operating systems and complex network typologies. To find a position that is challenging, rewarding and provides an opportunity to expand my knowledge and abilities in creating client centric solutions. expertise in back-end and frontend development using different technologies like PHP, CI, MySQL, AJAX, Angular, Slack, JavaScript, GitHub, Single Page Responsive apps, Cross-platform apps and many more. To retrieve the best output, he placidly cooperates with the web designer to match the visual design intent.

2017 - 2018

Software Developer

80M. IO

Key Result Area

Mange a website and Wordpress and PHP Application. expertise in Website development using different technologies like PHP, Wordpress, MySQL, and many more.

2016 - 2017

Web Developer

AMICI Global Solution Pvt. Ltd.

Key Result Area

Mange all the website using HTML, CSS, PHP Application. expertise in Website development using different technologies like PHP, Wordpress, MySQL, and many more.



Projects URL

- https://teafloor.com/
- https://hpladditives.com/
- https://tcoe.in/
- https://www.essaycorp.com/
- http://www.primogroup.in/
- https://www.bonobology.com/
- https://dot.gov.in/



Projects

Project Name (1)	GuruQ
Organization	M & J Edtech Pvt. Ltd.
Tools & Technologies	React JS, Node Js, Express. Js, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, AWS, PHP, WordPress
Team Size & Duration	7, From Nov-2019 to Present
Role	DM-IT (Manage as a Team Lead)
Responsibility	 Team player with excellent communication, Trouble shooting, Debugging and Strong analytical problem solving skills to deliver Technology products and consulting solutions. Analyzed business requirement to translate functional requirements into technical requirements and developed web application using MongoDB, Express, React.js and Node.js (MERN stack). Used HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript to build Interactive User Interface (UI), created responsive web pages using react bootstrap framework. Worked on State, Props, and Events to create interactive and stateful React Components, achieved routing using react-router. Created class based and function based components, added necessary event listeners, implemented communication strategies between React Components. GIT was used as code repository as module bundler, JIRA for bug tracking for continuous integration code deployment. Active participant in daily scrum meetings and involved in many phases of Confidential using Agile methodology.
Description	GuruQ is India's best tutoring platform that connects students with the right tutors. With the GuruQ platform, students can personalize their tuitions classes with respect to the mode of class (Home or online), type of class (individual or group) and budget. Application Portal Features: Support all browser & devices on Web and App

Project Name (2)	HPL Additives
Organization	HPL additives
Tools & Technologies	HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery , PHP,AWS
Team Size & Duration	2 employees, From Dec-2021 to 01-May-2022.
Role	DM-IT
Responsibility	Work as a team member using HTML, CSS and JS as Front end and PHP, SQL Server as Backend. Actively involved in coding and during full execution of the SDLC. Code reviews for team. Manage code and release configuration on Live Server.
Description	A leader in Polymer Additives Industry HPL was founded in 1964. Over the last 5 decades, ithas established itself as a leader in the area of the of Chemical Blowing Agents (Exothermic and Endothermic) and has increased the product range to include Antioxidants, Azo- Initiators, Chain Extenders and Cross-Linking Agents for polymers, Water Treatment Chemicals, Specialty Chemicals, Hydrazine hydrate and Hydrazine derivatives.

Project Name (2)	Essaycorp
Organization	AMICI Global Solutions Pvt. Ltd
Tools & Technologies	PHP, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX.
Team Size & Duration	3 employees, From Feb-2016 to Dec-2016.
Role	Web Developer
Responsibility	Work as a Web Developer and manage all the design and development module.
Description	Essaycorp is the best assignment help provider and the right platform for every student who requires professional help with their academic assignments. We provide our assistance to all those students who search for an expert assignment help provider online. Our services are widespread across the USA, UK, Canada, Australia & New Zealand. Students from all over the world, land in with their assignments and set out with an A+grade.

Project Name (5)	OOFFRR
Organization	Primo Group
Client	Pradeep Sharma
Tools & Technologies	Angular, PHP,CI, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, API, POSTMAN, Angular
Team Size & Duration	8 employees, From Jan-2018 to Nov-2019.
Role	Sr. Software Engineer
Responsibility	Work as a team member using Angular, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap as Front end and PHP as Backend and MySQL is Data base. Actively involved in coding and during full execution of the SDLC. Involved in application architecture and Refactor code to make reusable component. Code reviews for team.
Description	Primo Group had registered its first company, Primo Integrated Services Pvt. Ltd., in 2011which provides complex Logistics Solutions and Warehousing and Inventory Management Services in India. Then in 2017 two other companies named Primo Hansford and Consulting Pvt. Ltd. and Primo Smart Future Pvt. Ltd. came into existence. Former company provides services such as Contract Staffing, Payroll Management, Facility Management & Statutory Compliance and Warehousing and Inventory Management Services in India to other companies like Snapdeal, Amazon, Jabong, Paytm, LimeRoad, Carlsberg, Kohinoor etc.

Personal Details

Name Dharmendra Kumar Singh

Father's Name Mr. Rajaram Singh

Present Address S59 School Block Shakarpur Laxminagar,

New Delhi-110092Date of Birth 18th April 1991

Marital Status Married
Nationality Indian
Language Known English, Hindi